Register of the Joseph Warren Stilwell papers 51001
Hoover Institution Archives
- China-Burma-India Command File, 1942-1945
  - File 60. Minutes and notes on a conference held at General Headquarters, New Delhi, 1942 October 27 (Box-folder 24: 4)
  - File 61.
    - Charts, maps, memoranda, and notes regarding the poor morale and condition of the Chinese, 1939-1943 (Box-folder 24: 5-7)
    - Summary of the Trident Conference, Washington, D.C., 1943 May (Box-folder 24: 8)
  - File 62. Memoranda, printed matter, and reports from John P. Davies to Joseph W. Stilwell, 1942 (Box-folder 24: 9-10)
  - File 63. Translation of "China's Destiny,", undated (Box-folder 24: 11)
  - File 64. Radiograms, sent and received, 1943 (Box-folder 24: 12)
  - File 65.
    - Letter from Edmund L. Gruber to Joseph W. Stilwell regarding the situation in the Chinese theater, 1942 July 28 (Box-folder 24: 13)
    - Letter from Frank Merrill to Joseph W. Stilwelln, 1943 September 26 (Box-folder 24: 14)
      Letter regarding the organization of the Southeast Asia Command.
    - Memorandum from the Office of the Deputy Commander, Southeast Asia Command, to Joseph W. Stilwell, 1943 September 18 (Box-folder 24: 15)
      Includes organizational chart.
    - Notes on Burma operations, undated (Box-folder 24: 16)
    - Report from Joseph W. Stilwell to Chiang Kai-shek, 1943 November 5 (Box-folder 24: 17)
  - File 66. General Headquarters Weekly Summary, no. 42, 1942 (Box-folder 24: 18)
  - File 67.
    - Letter from F. H. Osborn to Joseph W. Stilwell, 1943 (Box-folder 24: 19)
      Letter regarding recreation buildings at Ford Ord, California.
    - Letter from Shang Chen to Joseph W. Stilwell and memorandum to Joseph W. Stilwell, 1943 (Box-folder 24: 20)
    - Memorandum from Brehon Somervell to George Marshall, 1943 (Box-folder 24: 21)
    - Memorandum from Roger S. Fitch to the Adjutant General, 1943 (Box-folder 24: 22)
    - Memoranda from John P. Davies to Joseph W. Stilwell regarding conversations with Chou En-lai and Feng Yu-hsiang, 1943 March 15-16 (Box-folder 24: 23)
  - File 68. Draft plans for the Pacific Front, 1942 (Box-folder 24: 24)
  - File 69.
    - Letter from Breedom Case to Joseph W. Stilwell, undated (Box-folder 24: 25)
    - Letters from Frank Merrill to Joseph W. Stilwell, 1942 (Box-folder 24: 26)
    - Memorandum from Frank Merrill to Joseph W. Stilwell, 1942 (Box-folder 24: 27)
    - Report from Frank Dorn to Joseph W. Stilwell, 1942 September-October (Box-folder 24: 28)
      Report regarding the trails and roads between Assam and Burma.
    - Report from Frank Merrill to Joseph W. Stilwell, 1942 November (Box-folder 24: 29)
      Report about the trails and roads between Assam and Burma.
  - File 70. Charts and memoranda, 1942 (Box-folder 24: 30)
    Relating to the organization, ammunition requirements, clothing, and equipment of the Chinese Army.
  - File 71. Here's How: A Handbook for American Troops in China, by John P. Davies, with an introduction by Joseph W. Stilwell, 1943 (Box-folder 24: 31)
  - File 72.
    - Notes on the operation of the Royal Air Force in Burma, 1943 March 23-April 29 (Box-folder 24: 32)
    - Report from Frank Merrill, "Notes on Burma Campaign,", undated (Box-folder 24: 33)
  - File 73. Letter from Shang Chen to Joseph W. Stilwell, 1942 August 1 (Box-folder 24: 34)
    Letter regarding plans for Burma operations.
  - File 74. Report from J. L. Huan to R. A. Wheeler, 1942 September 12 (Box-folder 24: 35)
    Report about the future War Area Service Corps for the care of American personnel in China.
  - File 75. Report on British forces in India, undated (Box-folder 24: 36)
  - File 76. Report on American medium M-3 tanks in India, 1942 (Box-folder 24: 37)
  - File 77.
    - Letter from Ho Ying-chin to Joseph W. Stilwell, 1942 (Box-folder 24: 38)
      Regarding the organization of the headquarters of the Chinese forces in India.
    - Translation of Chiang Kai-shek's orders to Joseph W. Stilwell about the new 22nd and 38th Divisions and their commanders, 1942 (Box-folder 24: 39)
  - File 78. Archibald Wavell's report on the Burma operation, undated (Box-folder 24: 40)
  - File 79. Report comparing the geography of the United States with that of the China-Burma-India Theater, undated (Box-folder 24: 41)
  - File 80. Dutch report from P. F. J. Everard to Frank Dorn on the Southwest Pacific, 1942 (Box-folder 24: 42)
  - File 81. Documents relating to the organization of the Chinese government, the Military Commission of China, the Chinese Red Cross, and other groups, undated (Box-folder 24: 43)
  - File 82.
    - Letter from Chiang Kai-shek to Joseph W. Stilwell, 1942 December 23 (Box-folder 25: 1)
    - Letter from Ho Ying-chin to Joseph W. Stilwell, January 19, 1943; letter from Joseph W. Stilwell to Tseng Kwang-lin, February 6, 1943; and letter from Shang Chen to Joseph W. Stilwell, 1943 March 20 (Box-folder 25: 2)
    - Letter from Lin Wei to Joseph W. Stilwell concerning the Y-Force operations, undated (Box-folder 25: 3)
    - Letters from Liu Fei to Joseph W. Stilwell, 1942 November-December (Box-folder 25: 4)
      Letter regarding artillery assignments and inquiries of Frank Dorn and R. A. Wheeler.
    - Memorandum from Joseph W. Stilwell to Ho Ying-chin and Joseph W. Stilwell's notes, 1943 January 5 (Box-folder 25: 5)
  - File 83. Notes advising officers on health, living, and working in the Far East among the Chinese, 1943 (Box-folder 25: 6)
  - File 84. Correspondence, maps, memoranda, minutes of meetings, notes, and reports regarding the preparation of operations for autumn of 1942 (Box-folder 25: 7-11)
    See also map case, folder 39.
  - File 85. Memoranda and reports regarding the organization of the Headquarters of the Commanding General of the Chinese Expeditionary Force in India, 1943 (Box-folder 25: 12)
  - File 86.
    - Correspondence between Frank Dorn and Yu Ta-wei, 1943 February 1-2 (Box-folder 25: 13)
    - Letter from R. C. Chen to David Yu, 1943 March 20 (Box-folder 25: 14)
    - Memoranda from Frank Dorn to Yu Ta-wei, 1943 March 13-26 (Box-folder 25: 15)
  - File 87. Memoranda and paraphrases of telegrams regarding the China Defense Supplies program, 1943 (Box-folder 25: 16)
  - File 88. Draft chapters of campaign history, 1944 (Box-folder 25: 17-21)
    Sections 1-3, history, letters, map, memoranda, notes, orders, and recommendations for citations relating to the Galahad campaign.
  - File 89. Circulars, draft chapters, letters, memoranda, and notes used to prepare the chapter on Services of Supply operations for "History of the China-Burma-India Theater,", 1942-1944 (Box-folder 26: 1-6)
  - File 90.
    - Clippings, undated (Box-folder 26: 7)
    - Drafts and notes used to prepare the chapter on the 14th Air Force for "History of the China-Burma-India Theater,", 1941-1944 (Box-folder 26: 8-10)
  - File 91. Drafts and notes relating to French Indo-China, the Yunnan bandit incidents, the Yunnan-Burma railway, the border dispute between Burma and Yunnan, the Yunnan offensive, and Chiang Kai-shek, 1943-1944 (Box-folder 26: 11-12)
  - File 92. Booklet about the 4th graduating class of the Yunnan Training School, 1945 June 9 (Box-folder 26: 13)
  - File 93. Memoranda from Clayton L. Bissell to Joseph W. Stilwell, 1942 August 23 (Box-folder 26: 14)
    Includes a check slip, directive, and receipt.
  - File 94. Draft monographs relating to British operations, entitled “The Arakan-Imphal Problems in 1944,” 14 pages; “The Arakan-Imphal Problems,” 11 pages, and “The Tactical Picture in 1944,” 9 pages (Box-folder 26: 15)
  - File 95.
    - Draft report on China exchange problems, 1944 (Box-folder 26: 16)
    - Letters and memoranda, 1942-1944 (Box-folder 26: 17)
  - File 96.
    - Draft report on the Southeast Air Command, entitled "Lord Mountbatten's Four Points,", undated (Box-folder 26: 18)
    - Letter from Charles Willoughby to W. Mason Wright, 1944 December 2 (Box-folder 26: 19)
  - File 97. Notes and summary of Sextant, Trident, and Quadrant Conferences, 1943 (Box-folder 26: 20)
  - File 98. Letter from Hayden L. Boatner to Chih Hu Pu, Chief of Staff, Rear Echelon, relating to the organization of the Chinese Army at Ramgarh, India, 1943 June 11 (Box-folder 26: 21)
  - File 99. Report entitled, "30 Division Plan,", undated (Box-folder 26: 22)
    10 pages
  - File 100. Report entitled, "Lend-Lease to China" and tables, undated (Box-folder 26: 23)
    14 pages
  - File 101. Notes on the establishment of the Southeast Asia Command, undated (Box-folder 26: 24)
  - File 102. Draft report entitled "Study of Routes to China,", undated (Box-folder 26: 25)
    Includes notes for map of routes.
  - File 103. Draft reports and notes on pipeline project, 1944-1945 (Box-folder 26: 26)
  - File 104. Report entitled "The Fourteenth Air Force,", 1944 December 1 (Box-folder 26: 27)
    Includes a letter from Charles Willoughby to W. Mason Wright.
  - File 105. Circulars and directives, letter, memoranda, notes, and reports relating to the administrative organization of the China-Burma-India Theater, 1942-1944 (Box-folder 27: 1-6)
    Titles of draft reports include, "Administrative History of CBI," "Administration and Relations with other Headquarters," "Brief Administrative Growth with Some of Complexities Described," "Situation Existing when CBI Established, Early Days," and "Unification of Command at Kunming."
  - File 106.
    - Letter from John L. Mott to W. Mason Wright, 1945 March 3 (Box-folder 27: 7)
    - Memorandum from Gordon A. Rust to John L. Mott, 1945 February 28 (Box-folder 27: 8)
    - Notes and reports relating to the operations of the American Transport Command, undated (Box-folder 27: 9)
  - File 107. Notes on airfield construction, 1943 (Box-folder 27: 10)
  - File 108. Draft report on the Burma campaign, 1942 (Box-folder 27: 11)
  - File 109. Letters, lists, memoranda, notes, orders, printed matter, and reports relating to the general administration of the China-Burma-India Theater, 1942-1944 (Box-folder 27: 12-16)
  - File 110. Drafts, maps, notes, and operational and staff reports used to prepare various chapters of History of the China-Burma-India Theater., 1944 (Box-folder 27: 17-21)
    Chapters included are Airfield Construction, Chinese Fillers Fly the Hump to India, The End of 1943, Plants and Events, Fall 1943, and Reconstruction of the Burma Road. See also map case, folder 30.
  - File 111. Opening statement of Joseph W. Stilwell, U.S. Congress. House of Representatives. Committee on Appropriations. Subcommittee on U.S. War Dept., 1945 May 28 (Box-folder 27: 22)
  - File 112. Miscellaneous data relating to the American ground forces, 1945 (Box-folder 27: 23)
  - File 113.
    - Memoranda by John P. Davies, 1944 November 3 (Box-folder 27: 24)
    - Memorandum by John K. Emmerson, "The Policy of the 8th Route Army Toward Japanese Prisoners,", 1944 November 10 (Box-folder 27: 25)
    - Report by John P. Davies, 1944 November 19 (Box-folder 27: 36)
      Relating to the organization and operation of the Shanghai underground.
  - File 114.
    - Editorial, entitled "Date April 25th Is Near," Hsin Hua Jih Pao, 1945 March 3 (Box-folder 27: 27)
    - Yenan broadcast of comments on Chiang Kai-shek's March 1st speech, 1945 March 6 (Box-folder 27: 28)
  - File 115.
    - Letters from F. L. Eldridge to Joseph W. Stilwell and from John P. Davies, 1944 September 22, October 2 (Box-folder 27: 29)
    - Memoranda, including from Frank Merrill to Joseph W. Stilwell, 1944 September-October (Box-folder 27: 30)
    - Notes, undated (Box-folder 27: 31)
    - Outline plan of Operation Capital, 1944 (Box-folder 27: 32)
    - Report of Ho Ying-chin, 1944 October 1 (Box-folder 27: 33)
  - File 116. Strength reports, 1943 (Box-folder 27: 34)
  - File 117. Book, entitled Firings from Landing Craft with Standard Artillery and Rockets, Office of the Chief of Ordnance, Washington, D.C., 1944 (Box-folder 27: 35)
  - File 118. Campaign situation reports on East China, undated (Box-folder 27: 36-37)
    88 pages
  - File 119. Radio message book, "Shaduzup No. 5," of Joseph W. Stilwell's outgoing and incoming messages, undated (Box-folder 28: 1-3)
  - File 120. Radio message book, "Shaduzup No. 4," of Joseph W. Stilwell's outgoing and incoming messages, undated (Box-folder 28: 4-5)
    See also file 131.
  - File 121. Radio message book, "Shaduzup No. 3," of Joseph W. Stilwell's outgoing and incoming messages, circa 1944 (Box-folder 28: 6-7)
  - File 122. Radio messages and maps relating to the Salween Campaign, undated (Box-folder 28: 8-9)
  - File 123.
    - Draft of radio message from Joseph W. Stilwell, 1942 (Box-folder 28: 10)
      Message reporting on the evacuation of Burma in 1942 and his intention to reach Homalin.
    - Letter from Chiang Kai-shek to Joseph W. Stilwell, 1943 July 10 (Box-folder 28: 11)
  - File 124.
    - a. Radio messages sent to Joseph W. Stilwell, 1944 (Box-folder 28: 12-14)
    - b. Radio messages sent to Joseph W. Stilwell, 1944 (Box-folder 29: 1-5)
  - File 125.
    - Letter from H. H. Kung to Henry Morgenthau, Jr., 1944 April 19 (Box-folder 29: 6)
    - Memoranda, including from Benjamin Ferris, Everett Drumright, John P. Davies, John S. Service, and reports relating to the Chinese political situation, 1944 (Box-folder 29: 7)
    - Reports, 1944 (Box-folder 29: 8)
  - File 126. Plans for the training of the Chinese armored force, 1943 (Box-folder 29: 9)
  - File 127. Maps of the China-Burma-India Theater (Map-case folder 32)
    Including Hukawng Valley, Arakan Front, Trans-Turkestan Route, airfield in India Road, Bengal, Assam, India, and Burma.
  - File 128. Y-Force staff reports, 1944 (Box-folder 29: 10)
    See also map case, folder 40.
  - File 129. Y-Force staff reports, 1944 (Box-folder 29: 11)
  - File 130. Radio message book, "Book No. 8," of Joseph W. Stilwell's outgoing and incoming messages, undated (Box-folder 29: 12-13)
  - File 131. Radio message book, "Book No. 4," of Joseph W. Stilwell's outgoing and incoming messages, undated (Box-folder 29: 14-16)
    See also file 120.
  - File 132. Reports on Frank Merrill's Marauders, 1943-1944 (Box-folder 30: 1-2)
  - File 133.
    - Correspondence between Frank Dorn, Joseph W. Stilwell, and T. V. Soong, 1943 January 16-29 (Box-folder 30: 3)
    - Memoranda between Frank Dorn, Ho Ying-chin, Joseph W. Stilwell, and T. V. Soong, 1942 November 8 - 1943 January 29 (Box-folder 30: 4)
    - Notes by Joseph W. Stilwell, undated (Box-folder 30: 5)
  - File 134. Reports and lists on X-Force operations, 1942-1943 (Box-folder 30: 6)
  - File 135. Farewell letters from Joseph W. Stilwell to officers in the British, Chinese, and United States forces expressing his appreciation for their help, 1944 (Box-folder 30: 7)
  - File 136. Chart, memoranda, and notes on Y-Force ordnance requirements, 1942-1943 (Box-folder 30: 8-10)
  - File 137.
    - Correspondence between Frank Dorn and F. K. Sah, 1943 January (Box-folder 30: 11)
    - Memoranda and notes on Y-Force operations, 1942 December – 1943 March (Box-folder 30: 12-13)
  - File 138.
    - Conference minutes and notes relating to Chiang Kai-shek's "Three Demands,", 1942 September – 1943 January (Box-folder 30: 14)
    - Letter from Joseph Stilwell to Ho Ying-chin and paraphrase of Chiang Kai-shek's reply to President Franklin D. Roosevelt, 1943 September 22 (Box-folder 30: 15)
  - File 139. Charts, letters, memoranda, notes, and reports relating to the training program at Ramgarh, 1942-1943 (Box-folder 30: 16-21)
  - File 140.
    - Charts of 1st and 2nd Thirty Divisions, undated (Box-folder 30: 22)
    - Letters, including from Clayton L. Bissell to A. A. Waugh and Robert C. Oliver to Clayton L. Bissell, 1943 July 5, 23 (Box-folder 30: 23)
    - Memoranda, 1943 July 31 (Box-folder 30: 24-25)
      Including from Robert C. Oliver to Joseph W. Stilwell.
    - Situation map, 1944 September 4 (Map-case folder 41)
  - File 141. Map overlays on East China campaign, undated (Box-folder 30: 26)
    Includes messages, 1944. See also map case, folder 41.
  - File 142. Intelligence situation messages and reports, 1944 June-July (Box-folder 30: 27)
  - File 143. Imphal daily intelligence and operations situation reports, nos. 72-103, 1944 May 19-June 6, June 9-June 19, and July 15-July 20 (Box-folder 30: 28)
  - File 144.
    - Reports on requirements of Chinese divisions, 1943 (Box-folder 30: 29)
    - Tables of organization for the Chinese and Indian divisions, 1943 (Box-folder 30: 30)
  - File 145. Notes on airfield construction, airfreight, conditions in Assam, freight unloading, labor, the Ledo road, railways, and procurement problems in India, 1943 (Box-folder 30: 31)
  - File 146. Daily status reports, memoranda, and tables on Y-Force operations, 1943-1944 (Box-folder 31: 1-3)
  - File 147. Radio message book, "Shaduzup No. 7," of Joseph W. Stilwell's outgoing and incoming messages, undated (Box-folder 31: 4-5)
  - File 148. Radio message book, "Shaduzup No. 6," of Joseph W. Stilwell's outgoing and incoming messages, undated (Box-folder 31: 6-7)
  - File 149. Artillery plans for Y-Force operations, 1942 (Box-folder 31: 8)
  - File 150.
    - Draft letter from Joseph W. Stilwell to Yu Ta-wei, undated (Box-folder 31: 9)
    - Letter from Frank Dorn to J. L. Huang, 1943 March 15 (Box-folder 31: 10)
    - Memoranda from M. F. W. Oliver to Frank Dorn and from T. G. Hearn to Frank Dorn, 1942 November 20 - 1943 January 23 (Box-folder 31: 11)
    - Radio message from Joseph W. Stilwell to George C. Marshall, undated (Box-folder 31: 12)
    - Report on Tu Li-ming, undated (Box-folder 31: 13)
  - File 151. Plans of Chen Cheng and Joseph W. Stilwell for training Y-Force, 1943 January (Box-folder 31: 14)
    Including notes of a meeting between Chen Cheng, Joseph W. Stilwell, and T. V. Soong.
  - File 152. Letters, lists, and memoranda relating to the training school at Ramgarh, 1943 (Box-folder 31: 15-17)
  - File 153. Directives, letters, memoranda, and notes relating to the Y-Force Yunnan Training Center, 1943 (Box-folder 31: 18-20)
    Including from Frank Dorn to Joseph W. Stilwell.
  - File 154.
    - Conference report on the training school in India, 1942 January 22 (Box-folder 31: 21)
    - Letter and memoranda from Joseph W. Stilwell to Ho Ying-chin, 1943 January and March (Box-folder 31: 22)
    - Letter from Frank Dorn to Ho Ying-chin, 1943 March 19 (Box-folder 31: 23)
    - Letter from Tseng His-kuei to Joseph W. Stilwell, 1942 October 14 (Box-folder 31: 24)
      Including a translation of Ho Ying-chin's statement concerning the Burma campaign in an article, "China's War of Resistance in the Fifth Year."
    - Memorandum on Y-Force requirements, 1943 March 5 (Box-folder 31: 25)
    - Statement of Ho Ying-chin concerning the Burma campaign, undated (Box-folder 31: 26)
  - File 155.
    - Incoming radio messages for Joseph W. Stilwell, 1942-1945 (Box-folder 31: 27)
    - Letter from Henry L. Stimson to T. V. Soong, 1943 January 23 (Box-folder 31: 28)
    - Memoranda regarding modification of orders and the subject of Communist policy toward the Kuomintang, 1944 March-August (Box-folder 32: 1)
    - Minutes of an administrative staff conference and 134th Supreme Allied Commander meeting, 1944 June 9 and July 24 (Box-folder 32: 2)
    - Outgoing radio messages from Joseph W. Stilwell to George C. Marshall, 1942 (Box-folder 32: 3)
  - File 156. Incoming radio messages for Joseph W. Stilwell, 1942 December (Box-folder 32: 4)
  - File 157. Incoming radio messages for Joseph W. Stilwell, 1942 November (Box-folder 32: 5)
  - File 158.
    - Letter from the Chief of Staff to Joseph W. Stilwell concerning Stilwell's instructions, 1943 February 2 (Box-folder 32: 6)
      Includes U.S.-British agreement and T. V. Soong's correspondence.
    - Memorandum from Joseph W. Stilwell to Chiang Kai-shek concerning submitted reports, 1943 October 7 (Box-folder 32: 7)
    - Memorandum from L. T. Gerow to the Adjutant General concerning the designation of command, 1942 February 2 (Box-folder 32: 8)
    - Memorandum from Paul Linebarger to Colonel Dickey, 1944 September 8 (Box-folder 32: 9)
      Concerning the beating of the Chief of Conscription.
    - Policy paper, "A Policy Toward Japan," by John K. Emmerson, 1944 August 18 (Box-folder 32: 10)
  - File 159.
    - Chinese ordnance inventory, 1942 August 20 (Box-folder 32: 11)
    - Notes on a conference between Lauchlin Currie and General Yu Tai-wei, Chungking, 1942 July 31 (Box-folder 32: 12)
  - File 160.
    - Daily status reports on the American Transport Command operations, 1944 February (Box-folder 32: 13)
    - Incoming radio messages, 1943 March, September-October (Box-folder 32: 14)
    - Memoranda between Charles Willoughby and John L. Mott, 1944 October (Box-folder 32: 15)
    - Miscellaneous operational papers and a suggested outline for the history of the U.S. Air Force in the China-Burma-India Theater, 1943 (Box-folder 32: 16)
    - Notes on the 77th Brigade, 1944 (Box-folder 32: 17)
    - Outgoing radio messages, 1943 February 24, October 18 (Box-folder 32: 18)
  - File 161.
    - Letter from Chiang Kai-shek to two Chinese generals, undated (Box-folder 32: 19)
    - Letter from General Li-Tsung to Joseph W. Stilwell, 1944 August 18 (Box-folder 32: 20)
  - File 162. Draft chapters of "History of the China-Burma-India Theater,", undated (Box-folder 32: 21)
    Including chapter 14, "Burma Merry-Go-Round," and chapter 17, "Coda."
  - File 163.
    - Contract concerning the supply of hostel equipment, 1944 (Box-folder 32: 22)
    - Draft papers, 1943-1944 (Box-folder 32: 23)
      Includes, "History of the China-Burma-India Theater," entitled "Magruder Mission," "The 1942 Preparations for Opening the Burma Road," "Stilwell Begins to Shape the Mould," "Three Demands," and "Yoke Force, 1943-1944."
    - Notes about Lungling, China, undated (Box-folder 32: 24)
    - Report from John Magruder to Chief of Engineers, U.S. War Dept., 1942 January 29 (Box-folder 32: 25)
      Concerning the Yunnan-Burma Railway.
  - File 164. Memoranda, minutes, and notes on conferences with Chiang Kai-shek, 1942 June 26 and 29 (Box-folder 32: 26)
  - File 165. Draft chapters of "History of the China-Burma-India Theater," entitled "Miscellaneous Problems of 1944,", undated (Box-folder 32: 27-28)
    Chapter 15, and chapter 16 (no title).
  - File 166. Unit history, "History of the 679th Signal AW Company,", 1944 (Box-folder 32: 29)
  - File 167. Unit history, "History of the 679th Signal AW Company,", 1944 (Box-folder 32: 30)
  - File 168.
    - Chemical Warfare Service administrative report, "Chemical Warfare Service in CBI Theater,", undated (Box-folder 32: 31)
    - Letter from John A. MacLaughlin to Joseph W. Stilwell concerning the Chemical Warfare Service administrative report, 1944 January 6 (Box-folder 32: 32)
  - File 169.
    - General orders concerning the reorganization of the headquarters of the Y-Force Operations Staff, 1944 April 28, May 1 (Box-folder 32: 33)
      Including the joint administrative order no. 1, concerning plan of supply.
    - Letters, map, memoranda, and report concerning general Y-Force operations, 1944 (Box-folder 32: 34)
    - Memorandum from Frank Dorn to the Adjutant General concerning the historical report of the Y-Force Operations Staff, 1944 (Box-folder 32: 35)
  - File 170. Drafts and maps for the Planning Section for the China-Burma-India History Project, undated (Box-folder 32: 36-37)
    See also map case, folder 33.
  - File 171. Memoranda, radio messages, and reports concerning the activities of Milton E. Miles, circa 1944 (Box-folder 33: 1-3)
  - File 172.
    - Memorandum from Richard Weiser to Joseph W. Stilwell on the EAC Conference, 1944 June16 (Box-folder 33: 4)
      Concerning air supply capabilities.
    - Minutes of an administrative staff conference, 1944 June 9 (Box-folder 33: 5)